[
  {
    "id": 4701,
    "question": "extrañas",
    "questionDetails": "Los cuales tienen unas costumbres muy extrañas.",
    "answer": "strange, weird, miss",
    "answerDetails": "And they have some very strange habits."
  },
  {
    "id": 4702,
    "question": "jodida",
    "questionDetails": "Baja tu jodida voz.",
    "answer": "fucking, fucked, fucked up",
    "answerDetails": "Lower your fucking voice."
  },
  {
    "id": 4703,
    "question": "demostrado",
    "questionDetails": "Nosotros hemos demostrado rigor.",
    "answer": "shown, demonstrated, proven",
    "answerDetails": "We have shown rigour."
  },
  {
    "id": 4704,
    "question": "fotografías",
    "questionDetails": "Un panorama trató de componer dos piezas de fotografías.",
    "answer": "photographs, pictures",
    "answerDetails": "A panorama tried to compose two pieces of photographs."
  },
  {
    "id": 4705,
    "question": "adelantar",
    "questionDetails": "En esta carretera no se permite adelantar.",
    "answer": "overtake",
    "answerDetails": "You’re not allowed to overtake on this road."
  },
  {
    "id": 4706,
    "question": "restos",
    "questionDetails": "Después del Día de Acción de Gracias, usamos los restos del pavo para hacer una sopa.",
    "answer": "remains, wreckage, debris",
    "answerDetails": "After Thanksgiving, we use the remains of the turkey to make a soup."
  },
  {
    "id": 4707,
    "question": "entradas",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo entradas para el estreno para todas.",
    "answer": "tickets, entries, inputs",
    "answerDetails": "I got tickets for us all opening night."
  },
  {
    "id": 4708,
    "question": "to",
    "questionDetails": "In order to achieve his aims.",
    "answer": "para, con",
    "answerDetails": "Para conseguir SUS propósitos."
  },
  {
    "id": 4709,
    "question": "opina",
    "questionDetails": "Su doctor opina que usted necesita hacerse una punción lumbar …",
    "answer": "believes, think, feels",
    "answerDetails": "Your doctor believes you need a lumbar puncture or spinal tap …"
  },
  {
    "id": 4710,
    "question": "salte",
    "questionDetails": "Le dijo que salte al agua.",
    "answer": "jump, skip, springing up",
    "answerDetails": "You told her to jump into the water."
  },
  {
    "id": 4711,
    "question": "revistas",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo otra cara vendiendo revistas.",
    "answer": "magazines, journals, revues",
    "answerDetails": "Just another face selling magazines."
  },
  {
    "id": 4712,
    "question": "estable",
    "questionDetails": "Pensé que sería mejor conseguir un trabajo estable.",
    "answer": "steady",
    "answerDetails": "I thought I’d better get a steady job."
  },
  {
    "id": 4713,
    "question": "importó",
    "questionDetails": "A mí nunca me importó.",
    "answer": "mattered, imported, cared about",
    "answerDetails": "I never actually mattered, myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 4714,
    "question": "encuentres",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que encuentres a alguien que encaje.",
    "answer": "find, encounter",
    "answerDetails": "I hope you find someone who fits in."
  },
  {
    "id": 4715,
    "question": "apagado",
    "questionDetails": "Un vestido en tonos apagados de polvo azul y rosa polvoriento.",
    "answer": "muted",
    "answerDetails": "A dress in muted tones of powder blue and dusty pink."
  },
  {
    "id": 4716,
    "question": "copias",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito copias de los cuatro vídeos.",
    "answer": "copies, renditions, backups",
    "answerDetails": "I need copies of all four images."
  },
  {
    "id": 4717,
    "question": "ofrecerle",
    "questionDetails": "Deseo ofrecerle una palabra de consuelo en privado.",
    "answer": "offer",
    "answerDetails": "I wish to offer a word of comfort in private."
  },
  {
    "id": 4718,
    "question": "inocencia",
    "questionDetails": "Me encanta tu inocencia.",
    "answer": "innocence",
    "answerDetails": "I adore your innocence!"
  },
  {
    "id": 4719,
    "question": "bienestar",
    "questionDetails": "Un sistema sanitario centrado en el bienestar, no en la enfermedad.",
    "answer": "wellness, welfare",
    "answerDetails": "A healthcare system focused on wellness, not sickness."
  },
  {
    "id": 4720,
    "question": "equivocó",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie se equivocó en intentar romper la tensión.",
    "answer": "wrong, misspoke, screwed up",
    "answerDetails": "No one ever went wrong breaking the tension."
  },
  {
    "id": 4721,
    "question": "nadar",
    "questionDetails": "Los rusos fueron capaces de nadar sus portaaviones de infantería a través de.",
    "answer": "swim",
    "answerDetails": "The Russians were able to swim their infantry carriers across."
  },
  {
    "id": 4722,
    "question": "raza",
    "questionDetails": "Todos somos miembros de la raza humana sea el que sea el color o credo.",
    "answer": "race, breed",
    "answerDetails": "We’re all members of the human race regardless of color or creed."
  },
  {
    "id": 4723,
    "question": "pegaron",
    "questionDetails": "… limpiaba los gusanos parasitarios que se pegaron a otros peces.",
    "answer": "stuck",
    "answerDetails": "… cleaning the parasitic worms which stuck to other fish."
  },
  {
    "id": 4724,
    "question": "robaste",
    "questionDetails": "Le robaste su dinero.",
    "answer": "stole, robbed, swiped",
    "answerDetails": "You stole their money."
  },
  {
    "id": 4725,
    "question": "compre",
    "answer": "Buy"
  },
  {
    "id": 4726,
    "question": "encerrados",
    "questionDetails": "Me dijeron que los pacientes estaban encerrados en sus celdas.",
    "answer": "locked, enclosed, cooped up",
    "answerDetails": "You told me the patients were locked in their cells."
  },
  {
    "id": 4727,
    "question": "digno",
    "questionDetails": "Consejo digno, pero tedioso.",
    "answer": "worthy, deserving",
    "answerDetails": "Worthy but tedious advice."
  },
  {
    "id": 4728,
    "question": "palos",
    "questionDetails": "El jinete se cayó cuando el caballo golpeó los palos.",
    "answer": "rails",
    "answerDetails": "The rider fell off when his horse hit the rails."
  },
  {
    "id": 4729,
    "question": "reventar",
    "questionDetails": "Comimos casi hasta reventar.",
    "answer": "burst",
    "answerDetails": "And we ate till we nearly burst."
  },
  {
    "id": 4730,
    "question": "cambiaste",
    "questionDetails": "Le cambiaste la vida.",
    "answer": "changed",
    "answerDetails": "You changed her life."
  },
  {
    "id": 4731,
    "question": "cargando",
    "questionDetails": "Están cargando el barco.",
    "answer": "loading, charging, carrying",
    "answerDetails": "The boat is now loading."
  },
  {
    "id": 4732,
    "question": "preparé",
    "questionDetails": "Ya preparé una orden.",
    "answer": "prepared",
    "answerDetails": "I have prepared the order."
  },
  {
    "id": 4733,
    "question": "conductor",
    "questionDetails": "Mi padre es conductor del metro.",
    "answer": "driver",
    "answerDetails": "My father’s a metro driver."
  },
  {
    "id": 4734,
    "question": "convenció",
    "questionDetails": "Y eso nos convenció a todos.",
    "answer": "convinced, persuaded, coaxed",
    "answerDetails": "So that convinced us all."
  },
  {
    "id": 4735,
    "question": "aniversario",
    "questionDetails": "Mas en la víspera de mi aniversario el collar desapareció.",
    "answer": "birthday",
    "answerDetails": "The day before my birthday, the necklace disappeared."
  },
  {
    "id": 4736,
    "question": "fantasía",
    "questionDetails": "No Estoy segura de que Miriam sepa la diferencia entre la realidad y la fantasía.",
    "answer": "fancy, fantasia, fantasy",
    "answerDetails": "I’m not convinced Miriam knows the difference between fact and fancy."
  },
  {
    "id": 4737,
    "question": "perderlo",
    "questionDetails": "Puedo perderlo todo por esto.",
    "answer": "lose",
    "answerDetails": "I could lose everything over this."
  },
  {
    "id": 4738,
    "question": "preguntarme",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes preguntarme lo que quieras.",
    "answer": "ask me",
    "answerDetails": "You can ask me anything you like."
  },
  {
    "id": 4739,
    "question": "triple",
    "questionDetails": "Pero hagámoslo como una integral triple.",
    "answer": "triple, treble, tri",
    "answerDetails": "But let’s do it as a triple integral."
  },
  {
    "id": 4740,
    "question": "sentimental",
    "questionDetails": "Ésa era demasiado tierna y sentimental.",
    "answer": "sentimental, sentimentalist, sappy",
    "answerDetails": "That was so soft and sentimental."
  },
  {
    "id": 4741,
    "question": "apoya",
    "questionDetails": "La población apoya estas medidas.",
    "answer": "supports, endorses, rests",
    "answerDetails": "The public supports these measures."
  },
  {
    "id": 4742,
    "question": "regresen",
    "questionDetails": "Regresen a la estación inmediatamente.",
    "answer": "return, come back",
    "answerDetails": "Return to the station immediately."
  },
  {
    "id": 4743,
    "question": "traerte",
    "questionDetails": "Quise venir personalmente para traerte la noticia.",
    "answer": "bring",
    "answerDetails": "I wanted to come bring the news myself."
  },
  {
    "id": 4744,
    "question": "anuncio",
    "questionDetails": "Va a aparecer en un anuncio para crema de rasurar.",
    "answer": "ad, announcement, notice",
    "answerDetails": "She’s going to appear in an ad for shaving cream."
  },
  {
    "id": 4745,
    "question": "llamara",
    "questionDetails": "Incluso le dijeron que no llamara a su madre.",
    "answer": "call",
    "answerDetails": "They even told him not to call his mother."
  },
  {
    "id": 4746,
    "question": "inventó",
    "answer": "invention"
  },
  {
    "id": 4747,
    "question": "concreto",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo un interés concreto en la ley internacional.",
    "answer": "particular, specific",
    "answerDetails": "I have a particular interest in International Law."
  },
  {
    "id": 4748,
    "question": "seguirá",
    "questionDetails": "Lo seguirá haciendo hasta que alguien lo detenga.",
    "answer": "will",
    "answerDetails": "He will do so until he is stopped."
  },
  {
    "id": 4749,
    "question": "injusta",
    "questionDetails": "La vida es demasiado injusta.",
    "answer": "unfair, unjust, wrongful",
    "answerDetails": "Life is very unfair."
  },
  {
    "id": 4750,
    "question": "reserva",
    "questionDetails": "Reservas.",
    "answer": "reserves, booking, reservation",
    "answerDetails": "Energy reserves."
  },
  {
    "id": 4751,
    "question": "celebrarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Deberíamos salir y celebrarlo.",
    "answer": "celebrate",
    "answerDetails": "We should go out and celebrate."
  },
  {
    "id": 4752,
    "question": "sepamos",
    "questionDetails": "Puede que no sepamos cómo, pero sabemos por qué.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "We may not know how, but we know why."
  },
  {
    "id": 4753,
    "question": "adecuado",
    "questionDetails": "El nuevo presupuesto pretende asegurar niveles adecuados de personal a toda hora.",
    "answer": "appropriate, proper",
    "answerDetails": "The new budget seeks to ensure appropriate staffing levels at all times."
  },
  {
    "id": 4754,
    "question": "olla",
    "questionDetails": "Metió la pasta en la olla de agua.",
    "answer": "pot, cooker, saucepan",
    "answerDetails": "He put the pasta in the pot of water."
  },
  {
    "id": 4755,
    "question": "avanzando",
    "questionDetails": "El enemigo estaba avanzando.",
    "answer": "advancing, moving forward, progressing",
    "answerDetails": "The enemy was advancing."
  },
  {
    "id": 4756,
    "question": "cogí",
    "questionDetails": "Cogí este número de la nada.",
    "answer": "grabbed, took",
    "answerDetails": "I just grabbed this number out of the blue."
  },
  {
    "id": 4757,
    "question": "altas",
    "questionDetails": "Así que tiene amigos en las altas esferas.",
    "answer": "high, tall, upper",
    "answerDetails": "So he’s got friends in high places."
  },
  {
    "id": 4758,
    "question": "seremos",
    "questionDetails": "Ni siquiera seremos mencionados.",
    "answer": "be",
    "answerDetails": "We will not even be mentioned."
  },
  {
    "id": 4759,
    "question": "protege",
    "questionDetails": "Nuestros enemigos creen que les protege un viento divino.",
    "answer": "protects, safeguards, secures",
    "answerDetails": "Our enemies believe that a divine wind protects them."
  },
  {
    "id": 4760,
    "question": "daños",
    "questionDetails": "Encontré daños cerebrales pero no hay golpes en la cabeza.",
    "answer": "damage, harm, injury",
    "answerDetails": "I found brain damage but no bruises on her scalp."
  },
  {
    "id": 4761,
    "question": "paramos",
    "questionDetails": "Nos paramos en una curva.",
    "answer": "stopped, moors",
    "answerDetails": "We stopped on a corner."
  },
  {
    "id": 4762,
    "question": "abres",
    "questionDetails": "Abres las latas de cerveza con los dientes!",
    "answer": "open",
    "answerDetails": "You open beer cans with your teeth!"
  },
  {
    "id": 4763,
    "question": "pudieras",
    "questionDetails": "Quisiera que pudieras verme hoy.",
    "answer": "could",
    "answerDetails": "I wish you could see me tonight."
  },
  {
    "id": 4764,
    "question": "verán",
    "questionDetails": "Los niños disfrutarán el acuario. Verán muchos animales increíbles allí.",
    "answer": "they will see",
    "answerDetails": "The children will enjoy the acquarium. They will see lots of incredible animals there."
  },
  {
    "id": 4765,
    "question": "héroes",
    "questionDetails": "Necesitamos ser héroes como papá.",
    "answer": "heroes",
    "answerDetails": "We need to be heroes like dad."
  },
  {
    "id": 4766,
    "question": "levantado",
    "answer": "Raised"
  },
  {
    "id": 4767,
    "question": "llevará",
    "questionDetails": "Me llevará un par de días terminar el trabajo.",
    "answer": "it will take",
    "answerDetails": "It will take me a couple of days to finish the job."
  },
  {
    "id": 4768,
    "question": "suene",
    "questionDetails": "Hace que suene demasiado simple.",
    "answer": "sound, ring",
    "answerDetails": "You make it sound too simple."
  },
  {
    "id": 4769,
    "question": "bajan",
    "questionDetails": "… las burbujas suben y bajan.",
    "answer": "fall, descend",
    "answerDetails": "… as the bubbles continue to rise and fall."
  },
  {
    "id": 4770,
    "question": "consecuencia",
    "questionDetails": "Como consecuencia.",
    "answer": "consequence, result",
    "answerDetails": "As a consequence."
  },
  {
    "id": 4771,
    "question": "seguiremos",
    "questionDetails": "… nuestras leyes y lo seguiremos haciendo.",
    "answer": "continue",
    "answerDetails": "… our laws and will continue to do so."
  },
  {
    "id": 4772,
    "question": "colocar",
    "questionDetails": "Ella finalmente dijo que no podía colocarlo.",
    "answer": "place",
    "answerDetails": "She eventually said she couldn’t place him."
  },
  {
    "id": 4773,
    "question": "hágale",
    "questionDetails": "Hágale conocer sus sentimientos por él.",
    "answer": "make",
    "answerDetails": "Make your feelings known to him."
  },
  {
    "id": 4774,
    "question": "lucía",
    "answer": "Lucia"
  },
  {
    "id": 4775,
    "question": "decime",
    "questionDetails": "Decime dónde te ibas a encontrar con tus amigos.",
    "answer": "tell me",
    "answerDetails": "Tell me where you were going to meet your friends."
  },
  {
    "id": 4776,
    "question": "pinches",
    "questionDetails": "Conozco las pinches reglas.",
    "answer": "fucking",
    "answerDetails": "I know the fucking rules."
  },
  {
    "id": 4777,
    "question": "muchachas",
    "questionDetails": "Las muchachas están de camino.",
    "answer": "girls, young girls, gals",
    "answerDetails": "The girls are on their way."
  },
  {
    "id": 4778,
    "question": "euros",
    "questionDetails": "Cerca de seis millones de euros.",
    "answer": "euros, EUR, USD",
    "answerDetails": "About six million euros."
  },
  {
    "id": 4779,
    "question": "infeliz",
    "questionDetails": "Parece ser una mujer muy infeliz.",
    "answer": "unhappy",
    "answerDetails": "She seems to be a very unhappy woman."
  },
  {
    "id": 4780,
    "question": "cheque",
    "questionDetails": "Me mandaron un cheque por correo.",
    "answer": "check",
    "answerDetails": "They sent me a check by mail."
  },
  {
    "id": 4781,
    "question": "diablos",
    "questionDetails": "Diablos, otra vez voy a llegar tarde a mi clase de karate.",
    "answer": "heck, bloody hell, dang",
    "answerDetails": "Oh heck, I’m late again for my karate class."
  },
  {
    "id": 4782,
    "question": "helicóptero",
    "questionDetails": "Los helicópteros de la policía permanecían inmóviles sobrevolando el centro de la ciudad.",
    "answer": "chopper, helicopter",
    "answerDetails": "Police choppers hovered over the center of town."
  },
  {
    "id": 4783,
    "question": "gay",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que este tipo es gay.",
    "answer": "gay, queer",
    "answerDetails": "I think this guy’s gay."
  },
  {
    "id": 4784,
    "question": "cuídese",
    "questionDetails": "De acuerdo, cuídese.",
    "answer": "take care",
    "answerDetails": "All right, take care."
  },
  {
    "id": 4785,
    "question": "corrupción",
    "questionDetails": "La palabra ‘ adicto ‘ evoca el mal y la corrupción.",
    "answer": "corruption",
    "answerDetails": "The word ‘addict’ conjures up evil and corruption."
  },
  {
    "id": 4786,
    "question": "cuñada",
    "questionDetails": "y brindo por mi nueva cuñada.",
    "answer": "sister",
    "answerDetails": "And here’s to my new sister."
  },
  {
    "id": 4787,
    "question": "heridos",
    "questionDetails": "Los heridos salieron arrastrándose del autobús destrozado.",
    "answer": "injured",
    "answerDetails": "The injured crawled out of the wrecked bus."
  },
  {
    "id": 4788,
    "question": "ocultando",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que están todos ocultando algo.",
    "answer": "hiding, concealing, withholding",
    "answerDetails": "I think they’re all hiding something."
  },
  {
    "id": 4789,
    "question": "sentencia",
    "questionDetails": "Está previsto que dicte sentencia sobre el caso mañana.",
    "answer": "judgment, sentence, decision",
    "answerDetails": "He is due to pass judgment on the case tomorrow."
  },
  {
    "id": 4790,
    "question": "cañón",
    "questionDetails": "El granjero les metió el cañón de la escopeta en la cara.",
    "answer": "barrel",
    "answerDetails": "The farmer thrust the barrel of the shotgun in their faces."
  },
  {
    "id": 4791,
    "question": "casó",
    "questionDetails": "También se casó con un chico estupendo.",
    "answer": "married, wed",
    "answerDetails": "A really nice guy married me."
  },
  {
    "id": 4792,
    "question": "dolió",
    "questionDetails": "Eso parece que dolió.",
    "answer": "hurt, grieved",
    "answerDetails": "That looked like it hurt."
  },
  {
    "id": 4793,
    "question": "échale",
    "questionDetails": "Échale una mirada a esto.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "Take a look at this."
  },
  {
    "id": 4794,
    "question": "inconveniente",
    "questionDetails": "El único inconveniente de mi apartamento en Nueva York era que no tenía bañera.",
    "answer": "drawback, inconvenient, downside",
    "answerDetails": "The only drawback to my apartment in New York was it had no bathtub."
  },
  {
    "id": 4795,
    "question": "explicarle",
    "questionDetails": "Déjeme explicarle de dónde venimos.",
    "answer": "explain",
    "answerDetails": "I should explain where we come from."
  },
  {
    "id": 4796,
    "question": "invitada",
    "questionDetails": "Saludo a nuestra invitada con palabras de bienvenida.",
    "answer": "guest",
    "answerDetails": "Greet our guest with words of welcome."
  },
  {
    "id": 4797,
    "question": "cuernos",
    "questionDetails": "Y éstos son los cuernos.",
    "answer": "horns, horned, antlers",
    "answerDetails": "And these are the horns."
  },
  {
    "id": 4798,
    "question": "amaba",
    "questionDetails": "Amaba su trabajo y le dedicó su vida.",
    "answer": "she loved, he loved her",
    "answerDetails": "She loved her work and dedicated her life to it."
  },
  {
    "id": 4799,
    "question": "españoles",
    "questionDetails": "Los barcos españoles suelen ser lentos.",
    "answer": "spanish",
    "answerDetails": "Spanish ships are notoriously slow."
  },
  {
    "id": 4800,
    "question": "suicidio",
    "questionDetails": "Sufría de depresión e incluso había considerado el suicidio.",
    "answer": "suicide",
    "answerDetails": "I was suffering from depression and had even contemplated suicide."
  }
]